IBT0042
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Local Union 995 records
1969-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 995. Teamsters Local 995
IBT0042
0.5 Linear Feet
This collection consists of agreements between Local Union 995 in Las Vegas, Nevada and various employers, as well as the minutes of the Local's meetings.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of International Brotherhood of Teamsters [2013-007]
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically
Biographical / Historical
Professional, Clerical, Ground Maintenance, Parking Lot Attendants, Car Rental Employees, Warehousemen and Helpers, Local 995 was chartered in 1969. The local primarily covered the service employees in Las Vegas' casino and tourist industry.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials produced by or amassed by Local teamsters union 995. The collection currently consists of agreements between Local Union 995 and various parties, by-laws, meeting minutes, and mediation notices. The material ranges from 1969-2003
Labor unions -- Nevada -- Las Vegas -- History; Collective labor agreements; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Casinos -- Employees; International Brotherhood of Teamsters
- Agreement - Hertz Rental, 1969; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agreement - Resort Hotels, 1June 1973 - 31 May 1976; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Agreement - Las Vegas Hacienda, Inc. dba Hacienda Hotel, 1 Jue 1976 - 1 April 1980; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Agreement - Resort Hotels, 1 June 1976 - 1 April 1980; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Agreement - Resort Hotels, 2 April 1980 - 1 April 1983; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Agreement - Hilton Hotels Corporation, dba Flamingo Hilton, 2 April 1980 - 1 April 1983; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agreement - Riviera Operating Corporation, dba Riviera Hotel and Casino, 2 April 1998 - 1 April 2003; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agreement - Park Place Entertainment Corporation, dba Las Vegas Hilton, 1 April 1998 - 31 March 2003; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- By Laws - Local Union no 995, 5 February 1999; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Election Results, 7 January 1975; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ritual, n.d.; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Meeting Minutes - General Membership, 1968-1983; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Meeting Minutes - Executive Board, 1969-1982; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mediation - Caesars Palace, 31 January 1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mediation - Thunderbird Hotel, 31 Janaury 1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Mediation - Tropicana Country club, 31 Janaury 1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)